□ (+1) 858-291-2678 | 🗷 yxl190090@utdallas.edu | 🏕 yul091.github.io/liyufei.me/ | 🖸 yul091 | 🛅 Yufei(Ethan) Li | 💆 @CavMonkey

Summary_

I am a second-year computer science Ph.D. student advised by Prof. Wei Yang at the University of Texas at Dallas (UTD). My research interests are in Deep Learning, Natural Language Processing (NLP), and Data Mining. I am conducting research at the intersection of NLP, Computer Vision, Data Mining, and Software Engineering. I am also researching the explainable machine learning such as predictive uncertainty measurement.

Education

University of Texas at Dallas

Dallas, TX, U.S.

Ph.D. IN COMPUTATIONAL SCIENCE

2020 - Present

University of California, San Diego

San Diego, CA, U.S.

M.S. IN ELECTRICAL AND COMPUTER ENGINEERING

2018 - 2020

Thesis: Application of A* and Genetic Algorithm in TSP Path Planning Problem; Advisor: Dr. Farinaz Koushanfar

Xi'an Jiaotong University

Xi'an, Shaanxi, China

B.S. IN MECHANICAL ENGINEERING

2014 - 2018

Thesis: Aircraft fuel tank oil sloshing simulation based on SPH method and center of gravity distribution analysis; Advisor: Dr. Shuai Zheng

Publications_

SHARE: a System for Hierarchical Assistive Recipe Editing.

Lı, S., **Lı, Y.**, Nı, J., McAuley, J. | 2021 arXiv:2105.08185 (CoRR) [PDF]

- Proposed a task of controllable recipe editing: adapting a base recipe to satisfy a user-specified dietary constraint to assist an under-served population of home cooks.
- Tackled this problem with a hierarchical framework which performs simultaneous ingredient substitution via a Set Transformer, followed by conditional instruction generation using a Copy Attention network.

Estimating Predictive Uncertainty Under Program Data Distribution Shift.

LI, Y., CHEN, S., YANG, W. | 2021 arXiv:2107.10989 (CoRR) [PDF]

- Defined three real-world program distribution shifts based on practical software development scenarios.
- Investigated the effectiveness of existing uncertainty measurements under program distribution shifts and proposed a large-scale benchmark for their performance.
- Analyzed each method's pros and cons from a logic design perspective to inspire future uncertainty study in software applications.

GLIB: Towards Automated Test Oracle for Graphically-Rich Applications.

CHEN, K.*, LI, Y.*, CHEN, Y., FAN, C., HU, Z., YANG, W. | 29th Foundations of Software Engineering (FSE 2021) [PDF]

- · Proposed a code-based data augmentation approach for generating UI glitch images on game apps.
- · Designed & built a CNN model for UI glitch detection and localized the glitch area using a saliency map.

Work Experience ___

NEC Laboratories America, Inc.

Princeton, NJ, U.S. Jun 2021 - Aug 2021

RESEARCH INTERN, PyTorch

• Annotated name entities and relations with regular expression rules on CVE texts for distant supervision.

- Incorporated the pre-trained GPT-2 backbone into a sequence labeling framework for joint entity & relation extraction.
- Proposed a bootstrap training procedure for denoising distant labels and selecting high-quality instances.

SeekTruth Scientific and Technical Corporation

Beijing, China

RESEARCH INTERN, TENSORFLOW

Jul 2019 - Sep 2019

- Designed and boosted an adaptive discrimination definition model for objection detection.
- Designed a light-weight CNN model for identifying the direction of videos.
- Built a joint key point & pose recognition model for character detection.

Projects____

Yufei Li · Résumé

RESEARCH PROJECT, PyTorch

Jul 2020 - Sep 2020

- Proposed a low-cost offline metric for evaluating the generalizability of code embedding in software engineering applications.
- · Patched the existing pre-trained embedding based on the semantic metamorphic relationship in vector space to improve the generalizability.

Negative Sampling with Bias Correlation, Data Mining

San Diego, CA, U.S. Nov 2019 - Jun 2020

RESEARCH PROJECT, PyTorch

- Explained the unsuccessful performance of the popularity-based sampling scheme in terms of sampling bias introduced from the non-uniform negative sampling process.
- Proposed two ways to correct the bias and design related negative sampling distributions to boost accuracy from tradition Bayesian Personalized Ranking (BPR).

Pet Adoption Speed Prediction, Natural Language Processing

San Diego, CA, U.S.

RESEARCH PROJECT, TENSORFLOW

Jan 2019 - Mar 2019

- · Parsed and tokenized the description text of pets, encoded the words with word embedding.
- Designed & built a machine learning framework to combine image features & natural language meanings for popularity prediction.

Automatic Delivery Vehicle Design, Path Planning

San Diego, CA, U.S.

RESEARCH PROJECT, PYTHON & MATLAB

Mar 2019 - Jun 2019

- · Incorporated the Courier and TSP travel agent problems in designing autonomous delivery vehicles.
- Designed & built a dynamic path planning model combining genetic algorithm and A* algorithm that for path planning.

Awards

VEX Robotics International Competitions

TEAM COMPETITION, C LANGUAGE

- Excellent award and runner-up in 2017 VEX Robotics World Championship, Louisville, KY, U.S..
- Excellent award and runner-up in 2016 VEX Robotics Asia Open, Beijing, China.
- First class honor in 2016 VEX Robotics China Open, Xi'an, China.

Scholarship Awards

PERSONAL

- National encouragement scholarship 2017, top10% of the 300+ applicants.
- National encouragement scholarship 2016, top10% of the 300+ applicants.
- National encouragement scholarship 2015, top10% of the 300+ applicants.

YUFEI LI · RÉSUMÉ 2